A Guide to the Confederate States of America, Subsistence Department, Commissary Records, 1861-1865
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Confederate States of America, Subsistence Department, Commissary Records, 1861-1865
The Library of Virginia
31327
3.6 cu. ft. and 8 boxes
Confederate States of America, Subsistence Department
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from the Buchanan Town Improvement Society, Route 1, Box 243A, Buchanan, Virginia
Scope and Content
Records, 1861-1865, of Thomas T. S. Barton, acting commissary for the Subistence Department of the Confederate States of America, consisting of appointments, circulars, correspondence, financial records, orders, regulations, and other papers concerning Barton's work as commissary for the Confederacy in western Virginia. Records detail Barton's efforts to get supplies in western Virginia for the Confederate army, and provide information concerning daily rations for troops, teamsters, and others involved in the war effort. Also contain information on prices for pork, beef, flour, coffee, soap, and other items as well as the commissary expenditures. Papers also include Barton's personal correspondence.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I: Orders, Regulations, Circulars, and Appointments.
II: Correspondence.
III: Financial Records.
IV: Miscellaneous Material.
Contents List
- Series I: Orders, Circulars, Regulations, and Appointments, 1861-1865., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  - General Orders, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Orders, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Orders, 1863. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Orders, 1864. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Special Orders, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Special Orders, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Special Orders, 1863. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Special Orders, 1864. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Special Orders, 1865 and no date. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Order book, 1861-1862. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Post Orders, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Circulars, 1861. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Circulars, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Circulars, 186[2?]. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Circulars, 1863. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Circulars, 1864. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Circulars, 1865. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Regulations of the Subsistence Department, 1861, 1864. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Appointment as Brigade Commissary, Major, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1861-1865., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 1-2)
  - Letter book, 1861-1862. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Official Correspondence, May 1861. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Official Correspondence, June 1861. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Official Correspondence, July 1861. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Official Correspondence, August 1861. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Official Correspondence, September 1861. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Official Correspondence, October 1861. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Official Correspondence, November 1861. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Official Correspondence, December 1861. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Official Correspondence, January 1862. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Official Correspondence, February 1862. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Official Correspondence, March 1862. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Official Correspondence, April 1862. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Official Correspondence, May 1862. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Official Correspondence, June 1862. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Official Correspondence, July 1862. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Official Correspondence, August 1862. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Official Correspondence, September 1862. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Official Correspondence, October 1862. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Official Correspondence, November 1862. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Official Correspondence, December 1862. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Official Correspondence, January 1863. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Official Correspondence, February 1863. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Official Correspondence, April 1863. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Official Correspondence, June 1863. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Official Correspondence, July 1863. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Official Correspondence, August 1863. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Official Correspondence, September 1863. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Official Correspondence, October 1863. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Official Correspondence, November 1863. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Official Correspondence, December 1863. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Official Correspondence, January 1864. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Official Correspondence, February 1864. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Official Correspondence, March 1864. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Official Correspondence, April 1864. (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Official Correspondence, May 1864. (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Official Correspondence, June 1864. (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Official Correspondence, July 1864. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Official Correspondence, August 1864. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Official Correspondence, September 1864. (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Official Correspondence, October 1864. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Official Correspondence, November 1864. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Official Correspondence, December 1864. (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Official Correspondence, January 1865. (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Official Correspondence, February 1865. (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Official Correspondence, March 1865. (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Official Correspondence, April 1865. (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Official Correspondence, undated. (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Telegrams, 1861-1864. (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1863. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1864. (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Envelopes. (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Series III: Financial Records, 1861-1865., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 2-8)
  - Monthly Financial Records, July 1861. (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Monthly Financial Records, August 1861. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Monthly Financial Records, September 1861. (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Monthly Financial Records, October 1861. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Monthly Financial Records, November 1861. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Monthly Financial Records, December 1861. (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Monthly Financial Records, January 1862. (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Monthly Financial Records, February 1862. (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Monthly Financial Records, March 1862. (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Monthly Financial Records, april 1862. (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Monthly Financial Records, May 1862. (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Monthly Financial Records, June 1862. (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Monthly Financial Records, July 1862. (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Monthly Financial Records, October 1862. (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Monthly Financial Records, November 1862. (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Monthly Financial Records, April 1863. (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Monthly Financial Records, May 1863. (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Monthly Financial Records, July 1863. (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Monthly Financial Records, August 1863. (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Monthly Financial Records, September 1863. (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Monthly Financial Records, October 1863. (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Monthly Financial Records, November 1863. (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Monthly Financial Records, December 1863. (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Monthly Financial Records, January 1864. (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Monthly Financial Records, February 1864. (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Monthly Financial Records, March 1864. (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Monthly Financial Records, April 1864. (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Monthly Financial Records, May 1864. (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Monthly Financial Records, June 1864. (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Monthly Financial Records, July 1864. (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Monthly Financial Records, August 1864. (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Monthly Financial Records, September 1864. (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Monthly Financial Records, October 1864. (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Monthly Financial Records, November 1864. (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Monthly Financial Records, December 1864. (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Monthly Financial Records, January 1865, folder 1 of 2. (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Monthly Financial Records, January 1865, folder 2 of 2. (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Monthly Financial Records, February 1865. (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Monthly Financial Records, March 1865. (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Monthly Financial Records, April 1865. (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending September 1861, folder 1 of 2. (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending September 1861, folder 2 of 2. (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending December 1861. (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending March 1862. (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending June 1862. (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending September 1862. (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending December 1862. (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending September 1863. (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending December 1863. (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending March 1864. (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending June 1864. (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending September 1864. (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending December 1864. (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - Quarterly Financial Records ending March 1865. (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Miscellaneous financial records, 1861-1865. (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1861. (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1862. (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1863. (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Miscellanous receipts, 1864. (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1865 and undated. (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Price schedules. (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Reports of agents, 1864. (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Transportation invoices, 1864-1865. (Box 8, Folder 134)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Material., Extent: 1 box. (Box 8)
  - Printed material. (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Miscellaneous indexes. (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Miscellaneous documents. (Box 8, Folder 135)